fccincinnati.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy | MLSsoccer.com

 _RELATED:[Política de Privacidad_]

## MLSsoccer.com Privacy Statement

The MLS web site currently located at mlssoccer.com, and the subdomains thereof, as well as the individual Member Club sites, our official MLS digital application and any Member Club application on which this Privacy Policy is posted (collectively, the "Web Site") are made available by Major League Soccer, L.L.C. (the "League"), on behalf of itself and on behalf of the Member Clubs that are part of and licensed by the League (collectively, "MLS" or "we" or "us" or "our"). This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") explains our privacy practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information collected through the use of the Web Site and through our various online services and applications provided by MLS through the Web Site (the "Services").

By visiting the Web Site or using any Services, you are consenting to the practices and procedures described in this Privacy Policy and in the MLS Terms of Service.

### Information Collected

#### Personal Information

"Personal information" is information that allows us to identify you. The types of Personal Information that we may collect from you includes, your name, home address, e-mail address, phone number, date of birth, and account information, such as your username, password, credit card information and other payment information.

We may collect Personal Information from you on or through the Web Site or Services in a variety of ways, including, when you register on the Web Site, purchase a Service, participate in online contests, surveys or games, sign-up for a newsletter or subscription or purchase merchandise.

We also may, from time to time, receive Personal Information about you from third party sources to improve the Web Site and our Services, and for the various purposes outlined herein.

#### Device Identifiable Information

We may collect information that does not identify you personally, but is linked to your computer or device ("Device Identifiable Information"). We collect Device Identifiable Information from you in the normal course of operating our Website. When you visit our Website to browse, read or download information, we automatically collect information about your computer that your browser sends, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times, pages visited, and referring website addresses. We may use Device Identifiable Information we collect to analyze trends, help administer the Web Site, track the movement of visitors, to learn about and determine how much time visitors spend on each page of the Web Site, how visitors navigate throughout the Web Site or use the Services and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

We may also collect Device Identifiable Information through "cookies" or "web beacons" as explained below.

We may also collect information about your mobile device such as the type and model, operating system (e.g. iOS or Android), carrier name, mobile browser (e.g. Chrome, Safari), applications using our Website, and identifiers assigned to your device, such as its iOS Identifier for Advertising (IDFA), Android Advertising ID (AAID), or unique device identifier (a number uniquely given to your device by your device manufacturer), sometimes referred to as a mobile carrier ID.

We may also collect your location information, such as your zip code or the approximate geographic area provided by your Internet service provider (ISP) or location positioning information provided by the location services and GPS features of your mobile device when location services have been enabled.

#### Cookies

To help us serve you better, we may collect Device Identifiable Information from you through technologies such as "cookies" and "pixel tags" (which are also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels) or by tracking internet protocol (IP) addresses. "Cookies" are small data files that are stored by your web browser when you interact with a website. When you visit a webpage, the cookie sends back Device Identifiable Information. "Pixel tags" are small graphic images (usually invisible) that can be embedded in content and ads on a webpage that track usage of the Web Site and effectiveness of communication. These pixel tags can then be used to recognize our cookies and to monitor certain user interactions with a website. Cookies operate in the background, and you can turn them off if you wish by adjusting your Web browser settings, but doing so may impair your ability to use some of the features on the Web Site. We may use cookies to make the Web Site work better by, for example, remembering your preferences, keeping track of your login name, password and, if you want to buy things while on the Web Site, your "shopping cart."

For more information, you may review the FTC’s guide to opting out of online tracking for computers and mobile devices. You can also see the "Choice" section below for ways to opt-out.

In some cases, we have arrangements with third-parties, such as authorized Service Providers, agents or representatives, to collect and store the foregoing information on our behalf, to provide services in connection with hosting or the operation of the Web Site, or to facilitate reporting of analytics (such as with Google Analytics).

Although the Device Identifiable Information that we share, including the Device Identifiable Information that is not linked to your mobile device, does not identify you personally there is a risk that third parties who receive such information from us may be able to re-identify you through other information they gather.

Except for IP Addresses, we may match Device Identifiable Information with Personal Information that we may have from or about you, which would allow us to identify you, we may use this information to provide you with offers that are available where you physically are located.

#### Social Media

When using the Services or when using certain third party social networking services (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, Google +) (each a "Social Network"), you may have the option to connect your Service information and activity with your Social Network information and activity. If you authorize such a connection, you permit us to share or publish information about your Service activity with that Social Network and its users, and to access certain of your Social Network information, as disclosed to you at the time you consent to the connection. Information we may share with a Social Network may include, but is not limited to: technical information about your Service activity, your Service comments or the videos you watch on Service. Information we may access about you, with your consent, from a Social Network may include, but is not limited to, your basic Social Network information, your location data, your list of contacts, friends or followers and certain information about your activities on the Social Network. If you permit a connection between a Social Network and a Service, we (and that Social Network) may be able to identify you and to associate information received pursuant to the connection with information we already have about you. For more information, please review the privacy disclosures and terms of your Social Network account, which govern how that account information is collected and shared with us.

### How we may disclose your information

We will not use, disclose, or share your information except as described in this Privacy Policy.

The Personal Information and Device Identifiable Information we collect from you may be used by us and by third-party service providers, such as hosting providers, data management companies, address list hosting companies, e-mail service providers, analytics companies, distribution companies, fulfillment companies and payment processors (collectively, "Service Providers") for a variety of purposes, including to:

(i) contact you about the Web Site and/or Services you have requested;

(ii) provide you with Services or information you have requested, or products or services you have ordered or signed up for, such as newsletters;

(iii) confirm or fulfill an order you have made;

(iv) administer your participation in a contest, sweepstakes, promotion, survey or voting;

(v) in order to facilitate the operation or maintenance of the Web Site, the Services, our operations and internal record keeping; and

(vii) with your permission, send you promotional material or special offers from MLS, Member Clubs, our marketing partners or other third parties. If you no longer wish to receive promotional e-mails from us, or have your information shared with third parties as previously described, you may change your mind and/or your preferences by following the directions in the "Choices" section of the Privacy Policy below.

Our Service Providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and we do not authorize them to use or disclose your Personal Information for their own marketing or other purposes.

Users may send information about our Member Clubs, our products, the Services and/or the Web Site to their friends and family members by using an "E-mail to Friend" or similar feature on the Web Site or in an e-mail that we have sent them. We do not further contact those individuals without their consent to do so.

_Third-Party Marketers._ With your permission, we may share your Personal Information with our marketing partners and other third parties so that they may contact you directly regarding special promotions or offers (such as subscriptions to and promotions for goods and services, including, for example, through participation in a co-sponsored sweepstakes or contest). We are not responsible for how these third parties may use your Personal Information, and such uses are subject to their own policies. **If you have consented to share your Personal Information with third parties for such third parties’ marketing purposes, you can change your mind at any time and may let us know by following the instructions in the"Choices" section below.**

_Aggregated Demographic Information._ We may use or share with third parties aggregated demographic information collected on or through the Web Site and Services for various purposes such as fan research and audience analysis. Aggregated demographic information does not include and is not linked to any Personal Information that can identify you or another individual person but we may use your to IP Addresses to verify users' locations for various purposes, including blackout restrictions.

_Other Disclosures:_ We may also share Personal Information and Device Identifiable Information under the following circumstances: (1) if required by law, such as by a court order, statute, regulation or rule, through legal process, or for law enforcement purposes; (2) in the event of a corporate transaction involving any of our businesses, such as the sale of that business or all or most of MLS’s or a Club’s assets or equity to another company; (3) in the event of a bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership or assignment for the benefit of our creditors; (4) if we determine it necessary in connection with an investigation or in order to protect our legal rights; or (5) in response to requests from federal, state, local or foreign law and civil enforcement agencies, such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order.

### California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the Personal Information we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please contact us at [Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u) or write to us at 420 Fifth Avenue, New York, NY 10018. Attn: Relations. Not all information sharing is covered by the "Shine The Light" requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response. Under California law, businesses are only required to respond to a request once during any calendar year.

### Chat rooms, forums and message boards

The Web Site may make chat rooms, forums, blogs, message boards and other community features and activities available to you and other users. If you post Personal Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personal Information in these areas. We reserve the right (but assume no obligation) to review and/or monitor any such community areas on the Web Site.

### Third party advertising

We may allow other companies (e.g., 24/7 Real Media) that are presenting advertising content, social networking or providing services on our pages to set and access cookies and other tracking technologies on your computer. These companies may collect information about your visits to the Web Site in order to measure and assess the effectiveness of online advertising and to provide and better target advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. While the information collected by these third parties from you while you are visiting our Web Site is not personally identifiable, some of these third parties may also combine such non-personal information with other information they have collected from various other sources, such as their own past online and/or offline purchase information and Web usage from other sites. Such other information may include Personal Information, as well as demographic and behavioral information. Those companies’ use of cookies, and the information collected, are governed by those companies’ privacy policies, not ours.

See the "Choices" section below for ways to opt-out.

### Short message service

We may make available a service through which you can receive messages on your wireless device via short message service ("SMS Service"). You understand that your wireless carrier’s standard rates apply to these messages.

If you subscribe to one of our SMS Services, you may be required to register and provide Personal Information. We may also collect the date, time and content of your messages in the course of your use of the SMS Service. We will use the information we obtain in connection with our SMS Service for the purpose of sending the SMS messages. If fees are charged to your wireless account invoice, we may provide your carrier with your applicable information to facilitate the transaction in connection therewith. Your wireless carrier and other service providers may also collect data about your wireless device usage, and their practices are governed by their own policies. We may also contact your carrier, which may access the content of your wireless account, for the purpose of identifying and resolving technical problems and/or service-related complaints. We do not guarantee that your use of the SMS Service will be private or secure, and we are not liable to you for any lack of privacy or security you may experience. You are fully responsible for taking precautions and providing security measures best suited for your situation and intended use of the SMS Service. You may change your mind and unsubscribe to SMS Services at any time by following the instructions in the "Choices" section below.

### Choices

You have various choices with respect to certain of our uses of the Personal Information we collect from you on or through the Web Site or Services. If you have not consented to us using your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy, we will only use it to complete the transaction or provide the service or product you have requested.

**If you have agreed to receive communications or solicitations from us (and signed up for an account with us), and you later change your mind, you can revise your preferences on the "Account" section of the Web Site or contact us at[Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u). You also may opt out of receiving all future promotional e-mails from us by clicking on an opt-out or "unsubscribe" link within the promotional e-mail you receive.** Please understand that if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your other relationship, activities, transactions and communications with us.

You may also opt out of our SMS messages by texting "STOP" or another applicable keyword to the short code applicable to the particular SMS Service (as further described below).

**If you have agreed to have us share your Personal Information with third parties so that they may contact you about promotions (and signed up for an account with us), offers and other information, you can revise your preferences on the "Account" section of the Web Site or contact us at[Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u).** If you do request to have us stop sharing your Personal Information with other entities for their direct marketing purposes, such request will only apply as of the date of your request, and we will not be responsible for any communications that you may receive from entities that received your Personal Information prior to such request. In these cases, please contact that entity directly or click on the opt-out or "unsubscribe" link that should be included within the promotional e-mail you receive from such third party.

You may opt-out of receiving ads from network advertisers by clicking the AdChoices icon on advertisements that are sent to you, visiting the opt-out pages on the NAI website ([access the NAI’s opt-out tool](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)) and the DAA website ([access the DAA’s opt-out tool](http://optout.aboutads.info/)). Opting out does not prevent you from seeing ads; it simply means that network advertisers will no longer collect data for the purpose of providing you targeted ads. The DAA and NAI opt-out tools are cookie-based. They signal network advertisers so that they do not collect data online or deliver specific ads targeting you, and only affect the Internet/web browser on the computer where the cookies are installed. These opt-out tools will only function if your browser is set to accept third-party cookies. If you delete an opt-out cookie or all your cookies from a browser's cookie files, change web browsers or change computers, you will no longer be opted out of our data collection and ad targeting, and we may place a new cookie unless an opt-out cookie is again reset on that browser. Opting out using one browser on one computer will not opt you out using any other browser on the same or another computer.

### Security practices

We use reasonable security efforts to protect the data in our possession. However, no method of transmission or storage of data is 100% secure and we will not be responsible for any damage that results from a security breach of data or the unauthorized access to or use of information, whether Personal Information or Device Identifiable Information. To the extent we provide your Personal Information to any third parties, we will request that they use reasonable security measures to protect your information.

### Accessing, reviewing, updating, correcting or deleting your personal information

If you want to access, review, update or correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information, or delete your Personal Information, you can revise your preferences on the Web Site or contact us at [Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u) or write to us at 420 Fifth Avenue, New York, NY 10018, Attn: Legal. Upon receiving your communication, we will take appropriate steps to update or correct such information in our possession, or to remove you from our catalog and mailing list. Your preferences include, for example, your profile information, as well as any shipping, payment and account information (if applicable), as well as whether you want to receive communications from us. You can access your preferences by logging-in to your account. If you want to close your account with us and have us delete the Personal Information in it (except for information that we keep for record-keeping purposes), you should contact us at [Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u). We may request certain Personal Information for the purposes of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to their personal information records. Please note that if you request deletion of your Personal Information by MLS, your information will be deleted from MLS as well as all MLS Club databases.

### Links to other websites and services

The Web Site may contain links to other websites and online services. When you link to such other sites and services (including by means of clicking on hyperlinks, logos, widgets, banners or advertisements), you become subject to their terms of use and privacy policies posted thereon and/or applicable thereto. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you click on a link and leave the Web Site, and to read the privacy policies of every website that collects Personal Information from you.

### Additional information

The Web Site is operated and maintained within the U.S. We make no assurances or representations of any kind that the Web Site is suitable for use outside the U.S. or in the country in which you reside. The information we collect is kept on servers in the U.S. and may be transferred to servers in other countries, subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We retain the Personal Information that we collect for so long as we continue to have a business purpose for it.

By accessing the Web Site, using a Service, establishing an account or making a purchase, you consent to the processing of your Personal Information as provided in this Privacy Policy. You may withdraw that consent by contacting us at [Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u). You are required to provide certain Personal Information in order to use a Service, to make a purchase or to take advantage of certain features available through the Web Site. Your failure to provide such information may preclude you from using the Services or Web Site or may subject your account to termination, prevent you from making a purchase or prohibit you from using certain features.

If you wish to object to or raise a complaint on how we have handled your Personal Information, you may contact us at [Major League Soccer Privacy Policy Request](https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=hslDPaqBtU-nNMOAt8hHpZWgX73AZz1HidlattlTrqdUQ0c5NjlZVFA5Wjg3TExJOVJEMzZSR0FEVy4u).

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe our processing of your Personal Information is not in accordance with law, you may register a complaint with a governmental authority. Major League Soccer, L.L.C. controls the Personal Information collected via the Web Site and Services.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

You should review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may modify it from time to time, and such changes will be effective upon our posting them to the Web Site. Where consistent with applicable law, your continued use of the Web Site and/or the Services after we have changed the Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of the revised terms. Under certain circumstances (e.g., with respect to certain material changes to this Privacy Policy), we may also elect to notify you through additional means, such as posting a notice on the front page of the Web Site or by means of an e-mail that gives you the opportunity to indicate whether you consent to the proposed change.

### Special rules for children

_General Rules._ Although most portions of the Web Site are directed to general audiences, we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 18. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Information from a child under 18 without verification of parental consent, we will endeavor to delete that information.

_Information Collected and Parental Rights._ If your child wants to register on or participate in certain activities in the areas of the Web Site that are directed to children under 18, we will only do so if we have your consent. During the registration process, we may collect certain information from your child, including Personal Information such as their name or e-mail address, as well as a parent or guardian’s email address in order to obtain your consent. We will then send you an e-mail (which will include a link to this Privacy Policy), advising you about the portion of the Web Site in which your child has expressed interest, and request that you reply by e-mail if you consent to your child’s participation. In the reply e-mail, we may request further Personal Information from you (as defined in the main part of this Privacy Policy) about you and/or your child, but we will not request such information from your child. We will then send you a confirmatory e-mail of your child’s registration. Once your children are registered, we may request them to provide general information such as their favorite player. You have the right to review your child’s Personal Information, to have that information deleted, and/or to refuse to permit its further collection or use. Parents can contact the Privacy Administrator at the address or email asset forth at the end of this policy and we will respond to their requests.

_Information Use and Disclosure._ We – and any of our Member Club(s) the child indicates interest in – may use the Personal Information to provide the child with the special services for which he or she has registered, such as membership in a Kids Club, receipt of newsletters, or participation in contests. We do not condition a child's participation in any of our online activities on the disclosure of more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity.

Currently, the portions of the Web Site that are directed to children under 18 do not have unscreened chat rooms, blogs or other similar community functionality that would permit your child to disclose information to others or publicly. In addition, any "postcard" or "share with a friend" feature that may be available on these portions of the Web Site will collect the recipient’s e-mail address, but not the sender’s; permit the sender to type in a first name and last initial; supply the content or allow the sender to select a pre-determined message from a menu; and be sent immediately, at which time the recipient’s e-mail address as collected from the sender is deleted from our records.

Personal Information collected on or through any portions of our Web Site that are directed to children under 18 may be shared with Service Providers (as defined above) with whom we contract to operate the Web Site and some of the Services. These Service Providers will use such Personal Information of Web Site visitors only for the purposes of carrying out these operations. To the extent required or permitted by law, we may also collect, use and disclose such Personal Information in connection with security-related or law enforcement investigations or in the course of cooperating with authorities or complying with legal requirements. We may also use Web Site users’ information as permitted by law to protect our rights or property, our website, or its users and their safety. As set forth above, we endeavor to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of the Personal Information collected from your child. Other than our Service Providers and as described above, we will not share your child’s Personal Information with third parties.

### Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:  
Major League Soccer  
420 Fifth Avenue, 7th Floor  
New York, NY 10018-0223  
Attention: Privacy Administrator/Legal Department  
Phone: 212-450-1200
